noridianmedicare.com 2007-07-29

# Privacy Policy | Noridianmedicare.com

Noridian Administrative Services (NAS) takes your privacy very seriously. We actively protect the privacy of everyone who uses our Website. You do not have to give us personal information to visit our site.

## Web Server Usage

Any information collected will be used only by us and only for statistical purposes. We continually analyze user behavior in order to measure customer interest and to improve our Website. We may record information about how users access our Website. This information may include your IP address (or the DNS name associated with it) and what Web software you are using (browser and version). Information provided will only be used for statistical purposed to help improve this site. This information cannot be used to identify a specific individual. We may collect personally identifiable information (name, e-mail address, physical address, and other unique identifiers) only if specifically and knowingly provided by you. We will actively guard any personal information provided. We will not share personal information with any outside organization. While we make every attempt to protect the personal information that you share with us, it is important to realize that electronic mail is not secure against interception. If your communication is very sensitive, we recommend sending it by postal mail instead. NAS will not use email as a form of communication if it involves sensitive information. Only telephone, fax or postal services will be used for communicating sensitive information.

## Cookies

A cookie is a small piece of information that is sent to your browser when you access a Web site. There are two kinds of cookies, a session cookie and a persistent cookie. A session cookie is text that is stored temporarily in your computer's memory but never written to a drive. It is destroyed as soon as you close your browser. A persistent cookie is saved to a file on your hard drive. NAS primarily uses only session cookies. A persistent cookie that expires on its own in 30 days may be used in conjunction with a web site satisfaction survey, however no personal information is collected. You may be able to decline using cookies, but you may be asked to complete the web site satisfaction survey each time you access it.

## External Links

Our Website and publications contain numerous links to other network sites. We cannot be responsible for the privacy practices of other organizations or the content of external Websites.

## We Value Your Opinion

We welcome your input about our Website Privacy Policy. We encourage you to submit comments or questions to [webmaster@noridian.com](mailto:medicarewebmaster@noridian.com). Additional information is also available from CMS at [Privacy Act Information](http://www.cms.hhs.gov/PrivacyActof1974/) .
